

Edmonton, Canada

□ (587) 879-4626 | ■ tkuipers123@gmail.com | # tkuipers.ca | @ tkuipers | taligners | Tyler Kuipers | Tyler K

About Me

I am a senior level Software Developer with hands-on experience in many facets of software development including the SDLC, Agile methodologies, DevOps practices, and mentoring new developers. I am an enthusiastic, supportive team player dedicated to efficiently solving problems. I have proven experience leading teams, helping mentor junior developers, and performing well both individually and in group settings.

Work Experience_

Alberta Motor Association

INSURANCE SOFTWARE ARCHITECT

Jan 2023 - Present

I am working as a Software Architect on AMA's insurance systems. Responsibilities include the following:

- Architecting and developing the cloud architecture for AMA's pay-as-you-go insurance policy, accounting for > 1400 new policies sold in the first 4 months. (AWS, Terraform, Java)
- Architecting and helping to implement large updates to our online payment system, helping to enable an omnichannel experience with our insurance policies.
- Architecting and implementing a devops tool to allow our team to
 - create new testing environments in a single command, resulting in a > 90% reduction in time to create new environments. (AWS, Terraform, Python, Jenkins, Docker, Git)
 - create testing databases in a single command, resulting in drastically reduced time to diagnose production issues. (AWS, Terraform, Python)
- Architecting and developing our insurance platform's RESTful APIs to enable our online auto sales platform. (OpenAPI, Gosu, Typescript, Playwright)
- Code reviewing and testing various patches submitted by other developers. (Git, GitHub)
- · Improving, enforcing, and gathering feedback on coding standards across the insurance development team, resulting in increased code maintainability and reliability.
- Helping new developers learn how to approach legacy code throughout the insurance platform.

Vinted Sept 2022 - Dec 2022 SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

I worked as a Software Developer at Vinted on their shipping platform.

- · Working on high level design and implementation of a new shipping platform. (Ruby on Rails, Shopify)
 - Writing automated tests for the new shipping platform.

Arterys Inc. (Aquired by Tempus Labs)

Calgary, Alberta (Remote)

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER Aug 2021 - Aug 2022

I worked as a Software Developer for Arterys on their core platform. Responsibilities include the following:

- Working to integrate various medical detection AI models onto our platform. (Typescript, NodeJS)
 - Various bug fixes and feature enhancements throughout the product. (Typescript, NodeJS)
 - Working to lower turn-around-time on results of our AI algorithms. (AWS, Chef, Redis)
 - Code reviewing and testing various patches submitted by other developers. (Git, GitHub)
 - Helping new developers learn how to develop our product suite.
 - Monitor logs and other health checking platforms for problems before clients are impacted. (Elastic, FullStory, Kibana)

Alberta Motor Association

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER | SOFTWARE TEAM LEAD

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Jan 2018 - Jun 2018

Jun 2018 - Feb 2021 | Feb 2021 - Aug 2021

I worked as a Software Developer for AMA's Insurance Division, doing development on its core insurance product. Responsibilities included the following:

- Leading a team of developers working on the AMA's PolicyCenter implementation. (Gosu)
- Leading another team contributing to an organization-wide standards initiative.
- Performing scrum master responsibilities to increase team efficiency. (VSTS, Agile)
- · Suggesting and facilitating improvement ideas brought forward by the insurance development team.

I also brought success to our department in the following ways:

- · Led an initiative designing and programming the test framework. It has led to a sharp reduction in bugs throughout following projects.
- · Planned and implemented the solutions used for online payment on AMA's website, utilizing third-party APIs and Guidewire. (Gosu, JS, OAuth)
- Supported my team through knowledge transfer, guidance, and open dialogue.
- · Participated in upgrade assessment with Guidewire to determine the scope and amount of work required to upgrade AMA's instance of Guidewire to the cloud

Pleasant Solutions

I worked as a full-stack developer on projects highly customized to the client's needs.

• Created the HMI for a concrete distribution plant (C#, TDD).

- Gained experience in leadership roles for small projects.

AUGUST 11, 2024 Tyler Kuipers · Resume **Lockheed Martin Canada** Halifax, Nova Scotia Jan 2017 - Jan 2018

SOFTWARE ENGINEER ASSOCIATE

Worked as an associate software engineer developing software to be used in CMS 330.

- · Contributed to an internal research project, implementing a Data Fusion module for use with Combat Management Systems. (Java, XML, SQL, Oracle ESB)
- · Worked to develop software modules responsible for the management and status of various underwater sensors. (Java, Swing)
- Worked in an Agile SCRUM environment.

The King's University

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER/RESEARCH ASSISTANT

Edmonton, Alberta May 2014 - Sep 2016

Worked as a full stack developer; designed and implemented an approach to dynamically reference items both spatially and temporally.

- Designed and built a website that researchers could input information into; viewers could see the data and explore it. (PHP, HTML, VanillaJS, PostgreSQL, PostGIS)
- · Researched the method utilized and authored an undergraduate thesis documenting my contribution to the Edmonton River Atlas Website. (MFX)

Education

The Open University

Milton Keynes, England (Remote)

May 2024 - Ongoing

MSc. Computing (Software Engineering) Currently pursuing Master's in Computing at The Open University.

> Edmonton, Alberta Sep 2012 - Dec 2016

The King's University B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE